They often ask to recommend books about
часто вони просять порадити книги про
programming and but programming is such a
програмуванню і але програмування така
broad topic and I decided today to
досить широка тема і я вирішив сьогодні
recommend three books on design and
порадити три книги по проектуванню і
Each of these books will give you the opportunity to
Кожна з цих книг дасть можливість вам як
look at the program for developing a
би подивитися на програму на розробку
program a little from a different
програми трішечки з інших під іншим
angle from the others the books are like this they are straight the basics
кутом книги такі вони прям основа основ
I don't recommend any super hardcore now it's So where
Я не раджу зараз якогось супер хардкору
should you start and the first book
це То з чого варто почати і перша книга
is
- це
Robert Martin's Clean Architecture
чиста архітектура Роберта Мартіна
Cleaner Architect and it This book is cool because
клінер-архітектор і вона Ця книга класна
it describes How to structure
чим тим що вона описує Як структурувати
your backend how to break it into layers and what
ваш бекенд як його розбити на слої і яка
logic should be behind all this it's half the
логіка має бути за цим всім це половина
book the second half of the book is there a
книги друга половина книги - це там
parasol which is also very important so in
парасолід що теж дуже важливо тому в
principle such basic aspects are
принципі такі базові аспекти там
revealed there shown but they are very useful
розкриті показані але вони дуже корисні
in addition I will make videos on the channel
крім того я буду робити відео на каналі
I will already dig deeper into clean
Я вже буду глибше капатись чисту
architecture and I will not just
архітектуру і не буду просто
collect layers but I will show how
зібрати слої а буду показувати як
to implement each of the layers it should also
імплементувати кожен з слоїв теж має
be interesting so Subscribe like the
бути цікаво тому Підписуйтесь ставте
video will definitely be the
лайк відео точно буде таке
second book that I want to recommend is
другу книгу яку я хочу порадити це
Domain Level Design by Eric Evans and this
домейн рівень дизайн Еріка Еванса і ця
book It
книга Вона
explains  why is it important to be in the
пояснює чому важливо розмиратися в
subject area in fact the
предметної області насправді взагалі
book starts with the fact that
починається книга з того що
the recavens explains why some projects
рекейвенс пояснює чому деякі проекти
fail and some succeed why it is
провалюються а деякі успішні чому в
easy to add new features to some projects and
деякі проекти легко додати нові фічі а в
difficult to others and
деякі складно і
this book gives the answer how to design a
ця книга дає відповідь як спроектувати
project to make it easier to save asking
проект щоб полегшити спасе задавання
new things in this your if your program
нових речей в цю ваш якби ваша програма
your book
ваш букен
and it is worth reading it to the end even
і варто її дочитати до кінця навіть
once there was an interview with Eric Evans and
колись була інтерв'ю з еріком евансом І
he said that he regrets only one thing that
він казав що жалкує тільки про одне що
there is a very important topic about bounted Contex
там дуже важливо тему про bounted Contex
he put at the end of the book and not at the
він помістив в кінець книги а не на
beginning and this is one of such important
початок і це один з таких важливих
aspects to mobile design but
аспектів до мендрівних дизайну але
even if you read half of the book
навіть якщо ви прочитаєте половину книги
you are exactly how you will start differently where
Ви точно як ви почнете по-іншому де
many This book was a direct discovery
багатьох Ця книга була прям відкриттям
to look at development
дивитися на розробку
and the third book that I want to recommend is
і третю книгу яку я хочу порадити це
patrons of Enterprise application Rock
patrons of Enterprise application Rock
You corporate application templates by
You шаблони корпоративних приложений
Martin Fowler and it seems there Like in the
Мартіна фаулера і вона здається там Типу
title we have
в назві у нас
corporate there
корпоративні там
Enterprise and all that but in reality
Enterprise і все таке але насправді
No not so I don't know why it has this
Ні не так Я не знаю чому вона має оце
Enterprise name Maybe he
Enterprise назви Можливо він всіх
scares everyone but the book is very cool and
відлякує але книга дуже крута і на
unlike  from the hopov patterns which are
відміну від гоповських патернів які там
so tactical there are such most likely more
такі тактичні це такі скоріш за все
than strategic patterns most likely
скоріше за стратегічний патерни скоріш
you will not even
за все ви навіть їх не будете як би
implement them directly but you will meet
напряму імплементувати але Ви зустрінете
each of all the patterns there your
Кожен там всіх патернів вашому
your application That is you will see
вашому додатку Тобто ви будете побачити
how the orm works there how structured what
як працює там орм як структурована які
patterns inside the orm how to structure the
патерни всередині ормки як структурувати
bookend and by the way it will be directly connected the
бокенд і вона до речі буде пов'язана
book is not bad with pure architecture
прям книга непогано з чисто архітектурою
because pure architecture talks about
тому що чиста архітектура розповідає про
its own and here they just do
свої а тут якраз
not describe how to implement these layers so
не описують як реалізувати ці слої тому
it complements In addition it complements
воно доповнює Крім того вона доповнює
the ideas to my level design with all sorts of
ідеї до моїм рівень дизайн всякими там
patterns there Like there value objigsy and so on that is
патернами Типу там велью обжигси і так
in general it is useful because
далі тобто в цілому вона корисно тому що
it will give an understanding of how the
вона дасть розуміння того як
system works how they work in Free Work
система Працюють як працюють в Free Work
how orms work how large
як працюють ормки як працюють великі
programs and even small ones work and that is why I
програми і навіть невеликі і тому я цю
also actually recommend this book I hope this list is
книгу теж власне раджу сподіваюсь список
useful write in the comments your
цей корисний пишіть в коментарях свої
lists that is what books do you recommend what
списки тобто які книги ви радите які
books Maybe you have read these books and you
книги Можливо ви читали ці книги і ви
can give some of your own feedback
можете дати якийсь свій власний відгук
also write topics that you would like to
також пишіть теми які ви б хотіли ще
hear more on  channel and subscribe
почути на каналі і підписуйте